<resources>
    <!--important strings for app-->
    <string name="app_name">Fact Book</string>
    <string name="next_button">Next</string>
    <string name="previous_button">Prev</string>
    <string name="share_button">Share Fact</string>
    <string name="title_activity_home">HomeActivity</string>
    <string name="welcome_text">Hi, Select categories from menu or click next for random facts</string>
    <string name="car_facts">Facts about Cars</string>
    <string name="watch_ad_request">Watch an ad for me</string>
    <string name="solar_system">Solar system</string>
    <string name="car">Cars</string>
    <string name="category_navmenu">Category</string>
    <string name="rate_us_navmenu">Rate us</string>
    <string name="author_name">By Kuldeep Chilwal</string>
    <string name="about_text">Hi reader! I\'m an engineer by profession and Indian by heart. This app is a project I took to provide you with some cool facts about things we see everyday without the intrusive full screen ads! Hope you are enjoying it! This is just a beginning, stay with me because I\'ll be pushing some major updates soon! Keep sharing the app! Thank You :)</string>
    <string name="author_image_content_description">"Image of app's author "</string>
    <string name="donate_appeal_text">Help me code more! Buy me some coffee!!</string>
    <string name="donate_INR">DONATE IN INR</string>
    <string name="donate_USD">DONATE IN USD</string>
    <string name="about">About</string>
    <string name="about_author_menu_item_string">About</string>
    <string name="donate_menu_item_string">Donate </string>
    <string name="smartphone">Smartphone</string>
    <string name="human">Human</string>
    <string name="dog">Dog</string>
    <string name="spaceExplore">Space Exploration</string>
    <string name="cat">Cat</string>
    <string name="insect">Insects</string>
    <string name="shoes">Shoes</string>
    <string name="motorcycle">Motorcycle</string>


    <!--Facts about cars-->
    <string name="car1">The average fuel cost across all vehicles is 14.45 cents per mile, or about 23 miles per gallon.</string>
    <string name="car2">The best selling car of all-time is the Toyota Corolla.</string>
    <string name="car3">It would take less than a month to get to the moon by car</string>
    <string name="car4">The U.S. consumes about half of the world’s gasoline.</string>
    <string name="car5"> Ferrari manufactures a maximum of 14 cars a day.</string>
    <string name="car6">The average consumer spends $400 a year on diagnostics, scheduled maintenance, and tune-ups.</string>
    <string name="car7">The first windshield wipers were hand-operated.</string>
    <string name="car8">White is the most popular car color.</string>
    <string name="car9">The first cars did not have steering wheels. They were operated by a lever.</string>
    <string name="car10">It takes half an ounce of gas to start a car.</string>
    <string name="car11">The world’s first speeding ticket was issued in 1902</string>
    <string name="car12">1 in 4 cars on the UK’s road were made in China</string>
    <string name="car13">A modern Formula 1 car can drive upside down in a tunnel at 120mph</string>
    <string name="car14">60 million cars are produced every year</string>
    <string name="car15">The average car contains over 30,000 unique parts</string>
    <string name="car16">75% of all cars produced by Rolls Royce are still on the road</string>
    <string name="car17">The largest speeding fine ever produced was €1,000,000</string>
    <string name="car18">The world record for removing and replacing a car engine is 42 seconds</string>
    <string name="car19"> The odds of dying in a car accident are around 1 in 5,000</string>
    <string name="car20">The man who invented cruise control was blind</string>
    <string name="car21">The highest total mileage clocked by a single car is 2,850,000 million miles</string>
    <string name="car22">In 1916, 55% of all the cars in the WORLD were Model T Fords.</string>
    <string name="car23">Porsche’s first car was electric.</string>
    <string name="car24">South African drivers have the option to install flamethrowers on their cars.</string>
    <string name="car25">Whale oil was used in some car transmissions until 1973</string>
    <string name="car26">The Ford F150 is programmed with over 150 million lines of code</string>
    <string name="car27">U.S. auto production nearly stopped entirely during World War II</string>


    <!--Facts about solar system-->
    <string name="solarsystem1">Pluto is smaller in diameter than the U.S.</string>
    <string name="solarsystem2">You can make volcanos using water as magma. </string>
    <string name="solarsystem3">The edge of the solar system is 1,000 times farther away than Pluto.</string>
    <string name="solarsystem4">Almost everything on Earth is a rare element. </string>
    <string name="solarsystem5"> Jupiter has the biggest ocean of any planet, albeit made of metallic hydrogen.</string>
    <string name="solarsystem6"> The hottest planet isn’t closest to the sun</string>
    <string name="solarsystem7"> We live inside the sun.</string>
    <string name="solarsystem8"> Jupiter has had the same ongoing storm for 300 years and counting.</string>
    <string name="solarsystem9"> Neptune experiences wind speeds as fast as 1,600mph!</string>
    <string name="solarsystem10">You can grow as much as 5cm taller in space compared to on Earth.</string>
    <string name="solarsystem11">Venus the second brightest object in the night sky after the Moon.</string>
    <string name="solarsystem12">All planets were named after Roman and Greek gods and goddesses, except the Earth.</string>
    <string name="solarsystem13">Mars has two moons called Phobos and Deimos.</string>
    <string name="solarsystem14">Uranus is the second furthest planet from the Sun.</string>
    <string name="solarsystem15">It takes Uranus roughly 84 years to orbit once around the Sun. </string>
    <string name="solarsystem16">Mercury and Venus are the only 2 planets in our solar system that have no moons.</string>
    <string name="solarsystem17">If a star passes too close to a black hole, it can be torn apart.</string>
    <string name="solarsystem18">The hottest planet in our solar system is Venus.</string>
    <string name="solarsystem19">Our solar system is 4.57 billion years old.</string>
    <string name="solarsystem20">The Milky Way galaxy is 105,700 light-years wide.</string>
    <string name="solarsystem21">There are 79 known moons orbiting Jupiter.</string>

    <!-- Facts about smartphone-->
    <string name="smartphone1">The best-selling mobile phone is the Nokia 1100</string>
    <string name="smartphone2">In Ads, iPhones are Always Set to 9:41</string>
    <string name="smartphone3">The term Bluetooth comes from a Nordic king</string>
    <string name="smartphone4">There is a mobile phone out in space</string>
    <string name="smartphone5">Android Represents More Than 80% of the OS Market</string>
    <string name="smartphone6">The first call from a mobile phone was made on April 3, 1973</string>
    <string name="smartphone7">There is an addiction to mobile phones and it’s called nomophobia</string>
    <string name="smartphone8">We check our mobile phone about 150 times a day on average</string>
    <string name="smartphone9">There are already more mobile phones than people in our world</string>
    <string name="smartphone10">Mobile phones contain many more bacteria than a toilet flush</string>
    <string name="smartphone11"> the first Android phone was T-Mobile G1, aka HTC Dream introduced in the year 2008.</string>
    <string name="smartphone12">Google was prototyping their mobile software on a device known as the “Sooner“</string>
    <string name="smartphone13">In the year 2012, Apple sold 340,000 iPhones per day. </string>
    <string name="smartphone14">The Telephone Exchanges were the first setup in the US and they mentioned ‘Hello’ as the standard way to start a conversation on a phone in their manuals, which was then adopted world wide.</string>
    <string name="smartphone15">Apple was the first to include the front-facing camera on a smartphone with iPhone 4 in 2010.</string>
    <string name="smartphone16"> iPhone was the first smartphone to feature a successful Facetime Vidoe Calling.</string>
    <string name="smartphone17">90 percent of the phones in Japan are waterproof.</string>
    <string name="smartphone18"> Nokia 1100 was the only product in the history of electrical gadgets. It sold more than 250 million mobile phones.</string>
    <string name="smartphone19">In the United Kingdom, more than one million Smartphone people accidentally fall into the toilet every year.</string>
    <string name="smartphone20">90 percent of the world’s messages are read within 3 minutes of sending.</string>

    <!-- Facts about Human Beings-->
    <string name="human1">An average person breathes in around 11,000 litres of air every day.</string>
    <string name="human2">Your nose and ears continue growing throughout your entire life.</string>
    <string name="human3">Your sense of smell is around 10,000 times more sensitive than your sense of taste.</string>
    <string name="human4">The brain uses over a quarter of the oxygen used by the human body.</string>
    <string name="human5">The brain of an adult human weighs around 3 pounds (1.5 kg). Although it makes up just 2 per cent of the body’s weight, it uses around 20 per cent of its energy.</string>
    <string name="human6">When listening to music, your heartbeat will sync with the rhythm.</string>
    <string name="human7">In one year, a human heart would pump enough blood to fill an Olympic size pool.</string>
    <string name="human8">A large amount of the dust in your home is actually dead skin. Humans shed about 600,000 particles of skin every hour.</string>
    <string name="human9"> As well as having unique fingerprints, humans also have unique tongue prints.</string>
    <string name="human10">The cornea is the only part of the body with no blood supply – it gets its oxygen directly from the air.</string>
    <string name="human11">The liver is a serious multi-tasker, carrying out over 500 different roles.</string>
    <string name="human12">Every day the heart creates enough energy to drive a truck 20 miles.</string>
    <string name="human13">The average heart beats 80 times a minute! This adds up to around 115,000 times a day, or 42 million times a year!</string>
    <string name="human14">You’re more likely to have a heart attack on a Monday then on any other day of the week.</string>
    <string name="human15">There’s a one in three chance that your first heart attack will be your last.</string>
    <string name="human16">A females heart is smaller than a males by about 25%.</string>
    <string name="human17">It’s not just your cheeks that turn red and expose your embarrassment when you’re blushing. Your stomach also turns red, but not many people will notice this.</string>
    <string name="human18">Every 3-4 seconds, around 50,000 cells in your body will die and be replaced by new ones.</string>
    <string name="human19">It’s scientifically proven that children grow faster in the spring.</string>
    <string name="human20">After a long day at work, you will be around 8mm shorter than you were in the morning.</string>


    <!--Facts about Dogs-->
    <string name="dog1"> Three dogs survived the Titanic sinking</string>
    <string name="dog2">A Bloodhound’s sense of smell can be used as evidence in court</string>
    <string name="dog3">Basenji dogs don’t bark, they yodel</string>
    <string name="dog4">A Greyhound could beat a Cheetah in a long distance race</string>
    <string name="dog5">30% of Dalmatians are deaf in one ear</string>
    <string name="dog6">The Saluki is the oldest dog breed</string>
    <string name="dog7">Dogs have three eyelids</string>
    <string name="dog8">Dogs noses are wet to help absorb scent chemicals</string>
    <string name="dog9">Stray dogs in Russia have learned how to ride the complex subway system, and get off at specific stops in search of food.</string>
    <string name="dog10">Your dog can smell your feelings.They can in fact, smell things such as fear. When a human is fearful, they perspire, and a dog is easily able to pick up on this change.</string>
    <string name="dog11">According to Welsh legends faeries used to ride Corgis into battle.</string>
    <string name="dog12">Corgis were once used to herd cattle.</string>
    <string name="dog13">Queen Elizabeth II has owned over 30 Corgis in her lifetime!</string>
    <string name="dog14">The Great Dane is the tallest dog in the world, while the St. Bernard is the heaviest, weighing up to 120kg when fully-grown.</string>
    <string name="dog15">The Chihuahua is the smallest breed of dog in the world.</string>
    <string name="dog16">Dogs which live in the city will usually live longer than those who spend their lives in the countryside. </string>
    <string name="dog17">The world’s oldest dog lived to the grand old age of 29 years and 5 months.</string>
    <string name="dog18">The world’s smallest dog was a Yorkshire Terrier, which weighed just four ounces.</string>
    <string name="dog19">A dog was the first living creature to be sent into space.</string>
    <string name="dog20">Sometimes, a dog will chase its tail if it is suffering from fleas or anxiety.</string>

    <!--Facts about space exploration-->
    <string name="spaceExplore1">Total cost of the Apollo 11 mission that first put a man on the moon was $25.4 billion. In today’s money, that’s around $135 billion.</string>
    <string name="spaceExplore2">Space pens were developed by a private pen company, that spent around $1 million developing a pen that would work in a vacuum, with zero gravity, while undergoing extremes of temperature, before selling 400 of them to the space agency at $2.95 each.</string>
    <string name="spaceExplore3">In 2013, a Russian cosmonaut called Pavel Vinogradov was the first human to pay his income taxes from space.</string>
    <string name="spaceExplore4">Various astronauts who have been on missions there claim that the moon smells of wet ashes, or spent gunpowder.</string>
    <string name="spaceExplore5">Snoopy, from the Peanuts comics, is the astronauts\' personal safety mascot.</string>
    <string name="spaceExplore6">Explorer 1, launched on Jan. 31, 1958, was the first artificial satellite sent into space by the United States. It orbited Earth every 115 minutes, and its cargo included a cosmic ray detector designed to measure the radiation environment in Earth\'s orbit.</string>
    <string name="spaceExplore7"> Each space shuttle astronaut is allotted 3.8 pounds of food per day.</string>
    <string name="spaceExplore8">It takes six hours for a space shuttle, aboard a crawler-transporter, to make the trip from the vehicle assembly building to the launch pad preceding a mission.</string>
    <string name="spaceExplore9"> A manned rocket reaches the moon in less time than it took a stagecoach to travel the length of England.</string>
    <string name="spaceExplore10">There is no set number of people in an astronaut candidate class; NASA selects its candidates on an as-needed basis. To even apply to be an astronaut, candidates must have completed 1,000 hours of flying time in a jet aircraft.</string>
    <string name="spaceExplore11">There is one spacecraft currently orbiting Jupiter called Juno.</string>
<string name="spaceExplore12">Footprints left on the Moon won’t disappear as there is no wind.</string>
    <string name="spaceExplore13">A full NASA space suit costs $12,000,000.</string>
    <string name="spaceExplore14">On October 14, 1947, in the rocket powered Bell X-1, Capt. Charles E. Yeager flew faster than sound for the first time.</string>
    <string name="spaceExplore15">NASA became operational on October 1, 1958 -- one year after the Soviets launched Sputnik 1, the world\'s first artificial satellite.</string>
    <string name="spaceExplore16">The acronym "NASA" stands for National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</string>
    <string name="spaceExplore17">The Mercury, Gemini, and Apollo spacecraft landed in the Atlantic and Pacific Oceans when they returned to Earth.</string>
    <string name="spaceExplore18"> Astronaut Alan Shepard, the first American in space, to pee right inside his space suit.</string>
    <string name="spaceExplore19">Astronauts lose one percent of their muscle mass and as much as two percent of their bone mass with every month that they spend in space.</string>
    <string name="spaceExplore20">Premature aging is now recognized as one of the side effects of space travel.</string>

    <!--Facts about cats-->
    <string name="cat1">Cats are believed to be the only mammals who don’t taste sweetness.</string>
    <string name="cat2">Cats are nearsighted, but their peripheral vision and night vision are much better than that of humans.</string>
    <string name="cat3">Cats are supposed to have 18 toes (five toes on each front paw; four toes on each back paw).</string>
    <string name="cat4">Cats’ claws all curve downward, which means that they can’t climb down trees head-first. Instead, they have to back down the trunk.</string>
    <string name="cat5">Cats have an extra organ that allows them to taste scents on the air, which is why your cat stares at you with her mouth open from time to time.</string>
    <string name="cat6">Cats have whiskers on the backs of their front legs, as well.</string>
    <string name="cat7">Male cats are more likely to be left-pawed, while female cats are more likely to be right-pawed.</string>
    <string name="cat8">Cats live longer when they stay indoors.</string>
    <string name="cat9">Cats will refuse an unpalatable food to the point of starvation.</string>
    <string name="cat10">Despite popular belief, many cats are actually lactose intolerant.</string>
    <string name="cat11">A male cat is called a Tom. A female cat can be a Molly or a Queen.</string>
    <string name="cat12">The higher the fall, the more likely a cat is to survive it.</string>
    <string name="cat13">Cat brains are very similar to human brains.</string>
    <string name="cat14">President Abraham Lincoln was a bit of a crazy cat lady.</string>
    <string name="cat15">The first cat to take a trip to space was called Félicette.</string>
    <string name="cat16">If you think of yourself as a “cat person”, you’re among 11.5% of people in the world.</string>
    <string name="cat17">The record for the largest number of kittens in the same litter was 19.</string>
    <string name="cat18">Over her lifetime, a cat called Dusty had a total of 420 kittens.</string>
    <string name="cat19">The oldest known cat to give birth was 30 years old.</string>
    <string name="cat20">There are around 60 different recognized breeds of cats worldwide.</string>

    <!--Facts about Insects-->
    <string name="insect1"> A ladybird might eat more than 5,000 insects in its lifetime!</string>
    <string name="insect2">Dragonflies have been on earth for 300 million years!</string>
    <string name="insect3"> A bee’s wings beat 190 times a second, that’s 11,400 times a minute.</string>
    <string name="insect4">Caterpillars have 12 eyes!</string>
    <string name="insect5">One dung beetle can drag 1,141 times its weight – that’s like a human pulling six double-decker buses!</string>
    <string name="insect6">A single honeybee colony can produce around 100kg of honey each year – that’s 220 jars</string>
    <string name="insect7">Bulldog ants can leap seven times the length of their bodies!</string>
    <string name="insect8">Mosquitos are attracted to smelly feet!</string>
    <string name="insect9"> Butterflies taste with their feet.</string>
    <string name="insect10"> Grasshoppers existed before dinosaurs!</string>
    <string name="insect11">Beetles are the most biodiverse group of creatures.</string>
    <string name="insect12">There are 10 quadrillion ants on the planet at any given moment</string>
    <string name="insect13">Insects inhale oxygen and exhale carbon dioxide through holes called spiracles in their exoskeleton.</string>
    <string name="insect14">The dragonfly had a wingspan of 2.5 feet (290 million to 250 million years ago).</string>
    <string name="insect15">Most insects only live for a few days or weeks as reproducing adults</string>
    <string name="insect16">The egg laying queens of colonies can life for decades.</string>
    <string name="insect17">The meadow froghopper insect can jump more than 100 times its height (about 28 inches)</string>
    <string name="insect18">All bugs are insects, but not all insets are bugs</string>
    <string name="insect19">Houseflies find sugar with their feet, which are 10 million times more sensitive than human tongues.</string>
    <string name="insect20">Ticks can grow from the size of a grain of rice to the size of a marble.</string>


    <!--Facts about shoes-->
    <string name="shoes1">Men were the first people to wear hee</string>
    <string name="shoes2">Platform shoes used to be worn by Greek actors to signify status.</string>
    <string name="shoes3">Sneakers got their name because their rubber soles do not make noise.</string>
    <string name="shoes4">Your salary might determine the type of shoes you wear to work.</string>
    <string name="shoes5">Audrey Hepburn could be credited with bringing loafers into style.</string>
    <string name="shoes6">Dr. Martens were originally considered practical working men\'s boots for their air-cushioned soles.</string>
    <string name="shoes7">Salvatore Ferragamo invented the wedge shoe when Italy was suffering from closed trade with other countries.</string>
    <string name="shoes8"> Havaianas are inspired by Japanese sandals.</string>
    <string name="shoes9">Even though hardly any photos of him exist on the Internet, Jeffrey Campbell is a real person.</string>
    <string name="shoes10">The red sole on Louboutins are inspired by an Andy Warhol drawing.</string>
    <string name="shoes11"> The first lady’s boot was designed for Queen Victoria in 1840.</string>
    <string name="shoes12">The present fashion of shoes was introduced into England in 1633.</string>
    <string name="shoes13"> In the ninth and tenth centuries the greatest princes of Europe wore wooden shoes.</string>
    <string name="shoes14">Slippers were in use before Shakespeare’s time, and were originally made “rights” and “lefts.”</string>
    <string name="shoes15">Sneakers were first made in America in 1916. They were originally called keds.</string>
    <string name="shoes16"> The open-toed shoe became fashionable in the 1930s as a result of the new vogue for sunbathing.</string>
    <string name="shoes17">Roger-Henri Vivier is credited with inventing (or at least re-popularizing) the stiletto heel in the 1950s.</string>
    <string name="shoes18">The boots Neil Armstrong walked on the moon in are still floating around in space.</string>
    <string name="shoes19">In Biblical times a sandal was given as a sign of an oath.</string>
    <string name="shoes20">In Hungary the groom drinks a toast to his bride out of her wedding slipper.</string>

    <!--Facts about Motorcycles-->
    <string name="motorcycle1">The term "motorcycle" (or "motorrad" in German) was first used in 1894 by Hildebrand &amp; Wolfmüller.</string>
    <string name="motorcycle2">The longest distance a man rode a motorcycle in 24 hours was 3,256.5 km (2023.5 miles).</string>
    <string name="motorcycle3">Japan once built a motorcycle that was indirectly powered by human waste. Its name is the Toilet Bike Neo, and its creator is high-end toilet manufacturer Toto</string>
    <string name="motorcycle4">The first-ever Harley-Davidson motorcycle only went 25 mph (40 kph). It also had a single-cylinder engine that initially used an empty tomato can for its carburetor.</string>
    <string name="motorcycle5">Sixty-eight percent of the female motorcyclists who died in crashes in 2016 were passengers, and their deaths represented 92 percent of the passenger deaths.</string>
    <string name="motorcycle6">Suzuki originally began making weaving looms for Japan’s silk industry in the early part of the 1900s.</string>
    <string name="motorcycle7">Dodge built and sold nine motorcycles with a Viper V-10 engine called the Dodge Tomahawk. </string>
    <string name="motorcycle8">Modern sports bike tires don’t contain any actual rubber in them.</string>
    <string name="motorcycle9">The longest distance for riding a motorcycle was 2,019.4 miles in a 24 hour period.</string>
    <string name="motorcycle10">The first gas-powered motorcycle was invented by Gottlieb Daimler of Germany in 1885.</string>
    <string name="motorcycle11">Helmet use was actually mandated following Colonel T.E. Lawrence‘s (Lawrence of Arabia) death in a motorcycle accident. </string>
    <string name="motorcycle12">Honda’s CBR Stands For “Cross Beam Racer”</string>
    <string name="motorcycle13">On average, motorcycles are about twice as fuel efficient as cars.</string>
    <string name="motorcycle14"> Honda is the most common brand stolen and Harley is the least.</string>
    <string name="motorcycle15">The first Harley Davidson motorcycle, built in 1903, used a tomato soup can for a carburetor.</string>
    <string name="motorcycle16">The first rider to ever go over 300 mph was Don Vesco in 1975, on a 1496cc Yamaha-engined streamliner.</string>
    <string name="motorcycle17">When rounding corners, 75% of a bike\'\s grip comes from the front tire.</string>
    <string name="motorcycle18">BMW is the only current major manufacturer to reject the use of telescopic forks on its big bikes.</string>
    <string name="motorcycle19"> The smallest functional motorcycle in the world is called Smalltoe, and Tom Wiberg built it.</string>
    <string name="motorcycle20">Yamaha actually started as a piano manufacturer.</string>


    <!-- This is an ad unit ID for an interstitial test ad. Replace with your own interstitial ad unit id.
     For more information, see https://support.google.com/admob/answer/3052638
  -->
    <string name="interstitial_ad_unit_id">YOUR_INTERSTITIAL_AD_UNIT_ID</string>
    <string name="thank_you_for_adviewing">Hi! Thank you for viewing this advertisement. This will keep me motivated.</string>
    <string name="watch_Adv">Watch Ad</string>


</resources>