<resources>
    <!--important strings for app-->
    <string name="app_name">Fact Book</string>
    <string name="next_button">Next</string>
    <string name="previous_button">Prev</string>
    <string name="share_button">Share Fact</string>
    <string name="title_activity_home">HomeActivity</string>
    <string name="welcome_text">Hi, Select categories from menu or click next for random facts</string>
    <string name="car_facts">Facts about Cars</string>
    <string name="watch_ad_request">Watch an ad for me</string>
    <string name="solar_system">Solar system</string>
    <string name="car">Cars</string>
    <string name="category_navmenu">Category</string>
    <string name="rate_us_navmenu">Rate us</string>
    <string name="placeholder_author">Kuldeep Chilwal</string>
    <string name="about_author">Hi! I absolutely love to try new technologies and I love to engineer things. So, here I am making this app and trying to learn new technology. Hope you like this app and kindly check my other apps and donate using link in the app.</string>
    <string name="author_image_content_description">"Image of app's author "</string>
    <string name="donate_appeal_text">Help me code more! Buy me some coffee!!</string>
    <string name="donate_INR">DONATE IN INR</string>
    <string name="donate_USD">DONATE IN USD</string>
    <string name="about">About</string>
    <string name="about_author_menu_item_string">About Author</string>
    <string name="donate_menu_item_string">Donate </string>

    <!--Facts about automobile-->
    <string name="car1">The average fuel cost across all vehicles is 14.45 cents per mile, or about 23 miles per gallon.</string>
    <string name="car2">The best selling car of all-time is the Toyota Corolla.</string>
    <string name="car3">It would take less than a month to get to the moon by car</string>
    <string name="car4">The U.S. consumes about half of the world’s gasoline.</string>
    <string name="car5"> Ferrari manufactures a maximum of 14 cars a day.</string>
    <string name="car6">The average consumer spends $400 a year on diagnostics, scheduled maintenance, and tune-ups.</string>
    <string name="car7">The first windshield wipers were hand-operated.</string>
    <string name="car8">White is the most popular car color.</string>
    <string name="car9">The first cars did not have steering wheels. They were operated by a lever.</string>
    <string name="car10">It takes half an ounce of gas to start a car.</string>

    <!--Facts about solar system-->
    <string name="solarsystem1">Pluto is smaller in diameter than the U.S.</string>
    <string name="solarsystem2">You can make volcanos using water as magma. </string>
    <string name="solarsystem3">The edge of the solar system is 1,000 times farther away than Pluto.</string>
    <string name="solarsystem4">Almost everything on Earth is a rare element. </string>
    <string name="solarsystem5"> Jupiter has the biggest ocean of any planet, albeit made of metallic hydrogen.</string>
    <string name="solarsystem6"> The hottest planet isn’t closest to the sun</string>
    <string name="solarsystem7"> We live inside the sun.</string>
    <string name="solarsystem8"> Jupiter has had the same ongoing storm for 300 years and counting.</string>
    <string name="solarsystem9"> Neptune experiences wind speeds as fast as 1,600mph!</string>
    <string name="solarsystem10">You can grow as much as 5cm taller in space compared to on Earth.</string>

    <!-- Facts about smartphone-->
    <string name="smartphone1">The best-selling mobile phone is the Nokia 1100</string>
    <string name="smartphone2">In Ads, iPhones are Always Set to 9:41</string>
    <string name="smartphone3">The term Bluetooth comes from a Nordic king</string>
    <string name="smartphone4">There is a mobile phone out in space</string>
    <string name="smartphone5">Android Represents More Than 80% of the OS Market</string>
    <string name="smartphone6">The first call from a mobile phone was made on April 3, 1973</string>
    <string name="smartphone7">There is an addiction to mobile phones and it’s called nomophobia</string>
    <string name="smartphone8">We check our mobile phone about 150 times a day on average</string>
    <string name="smartphone9">There are already more mobile phones than people in our world</string>
    <string name="smartphone10">Mobile phones contain many more bacteria than a toilet flush</string>

    <!-- Facts about Human Beings-->
    <string name="human1">An average person breathes in around 11,000 litres of air every day.</string>
    <string name="human2">Your nose and ears continue growing throughout your entire life.</string>
    <string name="human3">Your sense of smell is around 10,000 times more sensitive than your sense of taste.</string>
    <string name="human4">The brain uses over a quarter of the oxygen used by the human body.</string>
    <string name="human5">The brain of an adult human weighs around 3 pounds (1.5 kg). Although it makes up just 2 per cent of the body’s weight, it uses around 20 per cent of its energy.</string>
    <string name="human6">When listening to music, your heartbeat will sync with the rhythm.</string>
    <string name="human7">In one year, a human heart would pump enough blood to fill an Olympic size pool.</string>
    <string name="human8">A large amount of the dust in your home is actually dead skin. Humans shed about 600,000 particles of skin every hour.</string>
    <string name="human9"> As well as having unique fingerprints, humans also have unique tongue prints.</string>
    <string name="human10">The cornea is the only part of the body with no blood supply – it gets its oxygen directly from the air.</string>

    <!--Facts about Dogs-->
    <string name="dog1"> Three dogs survived the Titanic sinking</string>
    <string name="dog2">A Bloodhound’s sense of smell can be used as evidence in court</string>
    <string name="dog3">Basenji dogs don’t bark, they yodel</string>
    <string name="dog4">A Greyhound could beat a Cheetah in a long distance race</string>
    <string name="dog5">30% of Dalmatians are deaf in one ear</string>
    <string name="dog6">The Saluki is the oldest dog breed</string>
    <string name="dog7">Dogs have three eyelids</string>
    <string name="dog8">Dogs noses are wet to help absorb scent chemicals</string>
    <string name="dog9">Stray dogs in Russia have learned how to ride the complex subway system, and get off at specific stops in search of food.</string>
    <string name="dog10">Your dog can smell your feelings.They can in fact, smell things such as fear. When a human is fearful, they perspire, and a dog is easily able to pick up on this change.</string>
    <string name="smartphone">Smartphone</string>
    <string name="human">Human</string>
    <string name="dog">Dog</string>


</resources>